Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Artwork, 1931-1980; 8.5 oversized boxes
  - Artwork by others, ca. 1931-1978; 3 oversized boxes, 2 cartons
    - Nichols, John. [Portrait of Henry Miller], 1931?; 1 items. (Box 104, Folder 3)
      Oil painting, 56 x 67 cm. Signed on recto, "John Nichols, signed by Kate Nichols for Henry Miller."
    - Carlson, Diane. "Tree drawing", 1979; 1 items. (Box 104, Folder 4)
      Watercolor painting, 56 x 56 cm. Signed by the artist. Accompanied by a letter from Carlson to Miller.
    - Delaney, Beauford. [Untitled watercolor], 1962; 1 items. (Box 104, Folder 5)
      Watercolor, 50 x 66 cm. Signed by the artist.
    - Blei, Norbert. Klee bouquet, 1966; 1 items. (Box 123, Folder 1)
      Pastel drawing, 45 x 38 cm. Letter from Blei to Miller written on the same sheet.
    - Goodman, Rachel. Figure drawings, 1965; 15 items. (Box 123, Folder 2)
      Charcoal drawings, 60 x 45 cm.
    - Krol, Abram. Prints, undated; 10 items. (Box 123, Folder 3)
      Assorted numbered and signed prints.
    - Miscellaneous watercolors and prints by unidentified or minor artists, circa 1945-1970; 18 items. (Box 123, Folder 4)
      Various sizes.
    - Osterlund, Steven. Assorted works, 1968-1970; 5 items. (Box 123, Folder 5)
      Original watercolor titles include: Beginning of a farm; The gun-winners; and two untitled works. The print is a poster-sized limited reproduction of a nude woman.
    - Perlès, Alfred. Sketches, 1967; 2 items. (Box 123, Folder 6)
      Pen and pastel sketches entitled: Very bad likeness of Henry and Hoki; To Henry with love. Signed by the artist.
    - Scala, Mia. [Portrait of Henry Miller], 1967; 1 items. (Box 123, Folder 7)
      Watercolor, 60 x 45 cm. Signed by the artist.
    - Shatz, Bezalel. Oil portrait of Henry Miller, and a print, 1946; 2 items. (Box 123, Folder 8)
      Original oil on tracing paper, 53 x 42 cm., of a portrait of Henry Miller. Signed by the artist and inscribed to Henry Miller. One print of an untitled work.
    - Spare, Austin Osman. Assorted portraits of Henry Miller, circa 1945-1954; 4 items. (Box 123, Folder 9)
      Pencil sketches on wood panel, 38 x 29 cm. and 23 x 18 cm. Pencil and oil pastel sketch, 38 x 27 cm.; oil pastel, 34 x 26 cm. All signed by the artist.
    - Steiner, F. Florian. Henry Miller, Big Sur, 1962; 1 items. (Box 123, Folder 10)
      Photolithograph, 32 x 23 cm. Signed by the artist.
    - Unidentified landscape, undated; 1 items. (Box 123, Folder 11)
      Acrylic on paper, 45 x 58 cm. Signed H. Ab[illegible].
    - Zilzer, Gyula. Assorted charcoal rubbings, watercolors, and prints, 1964-1967; 27 items. (Box 123, Folder 12)
      Titles include: Kibbutz workers; Icarus; Vietnam; Henry; and others. Most are signed.
    - Copper relief portrait, undated; 1 items. (Box 138, Folder 5)
      Copper releif mounted on wood, 23 x 26 cm.
    - Shirai, Hiro. [Reposing nude female], circa 1978; 2 items. (Box 144)
      Terra cotta figurines, ca. 10 x 17 x 24 cm.
    - Shirai, Hiro. [Seated nude female], circa 1978; 2 items. (Box 145)
      Terra cotta figurines, ca. 40 x 15 x 15 cm.
    - Ueno, Ken-ichi. [Portrait of Henry Miller], 1965; 1 items. (Box 163, Folder 1)
      32 x 40 cm. Signed by the artist.
    - Ray, Man. [Box with wooden objects], undated; 1 items. (Box 163, Folder 2)
      Wood box, 40 x 30 x 5 cm. Initialed by the artist, and signed by the artist on the back. Lettered g/g.
  - Signed prints and posters, ca. 1948-1974; .5 oversized box
    This subseries consists of prints of Miller's watercolors and posters advertising Miller's work. Most are signed by Miller.
    - The Windsor Gallery: homage to Henry Miller, 1974; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 1)
      Signed exhibition poster, 75 x 52 cm. Features a reproduction of the Henry Miller watercolor The Joker.
    - Just a Brooklyn boy, undated; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 2)
      Print, 79 x 57 cm. Signed by Miller. No. 25/200.
    - Sarasota, undated; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 3)
      Print, 65 x 51 cm. Signed by Miller. No. 92/100.
    - [O lake of light], undated; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 13)
      Poster reproduction, 60 x 48 cm. Gift of Brooke Whiting, 1985.
    - Hindu wedding, 1948; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 14)
      Serigraph silkscreen print by Bezalel Schatz from a drawing by Miller, 58 x 36 cm. No. 58/200.
    - Henry Miller: Gallery 669, paintings & etchings, May 29-June 16, 1967; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 15)
      Exhibition poster for Gallery 669, 61 x 46 cm. Features two photographic images of Miller; one as a child, the other as an adult.
    - Assorted signed prints inscribed from Henry Miller to Barbara Sanford (nee Miller), 1970-1977; 7 items. (Box 166, Folder 16)
      Assorted signed prints and one poster featuring small reproductions of 13 paintings. Titles include: Blue face; Childish dream; Clownesque; Glow worm (no. 129/200); The gremlins; The procession.
- Audio and visual materials, 1944-1973; 1 box, 3 oversized boxes (.5 linear ft.)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  This series consists of films, records, and magnetic tape recordings.
  Arranged in subseries A-B as follows:
  A. Sound recordings, ca. 1944-1973 (1 box and 1 oversized box)
  B. Film, ca. 1971-1973 (2 oversized boxes).
  - Sound recordings, 1944-1973; 1 box, 1 oversized box (.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of recordings of Miller reading from several of his books, interviews with Miller, and some unidentified recordings. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Durrell: for USA." [Unidentified recording], undated; 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 1)
      1 record (2 s.), 12 in.
    - "Henry Miller recalls and reflects." New York: Riverside Records, 1956, 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 2)
      Modern Voices Series. 1 record ( 4 s.), 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm.
    - Just Wild About Harry. [Paris]: La Voix de L'Auteur, 1962, 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 3)
      1 record (4 s.), 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm.
    - "Henry Miller reading from his Tropic of Capricorn." The Library of Congress Division of Music, 1944 (1 of 2), 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 4)
      1 record (2 s.), 16 in, 33 rpm.
    - "Henry Miller reading from his Tropic of Capricorn." The Library of Congress Division of Music, 1944 (2 of 2), 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - "Henry Miller Reading From Tropic of Capricorn. Berkeley, California: Circle Editions, 1946, 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 6)
      1 record (2 s.), 12 in., 78 rpm.
    - The Smile at the Foot of the Ladder. [Paris]: La Voix de L'Auteur, 1962, 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 7)
      1 record (2 s.), 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm.
    - To Paint is to Love Again. [Paris]: La Voix de L'Auteur, 1961, 1 items. (Box 130, Folder 8)
      1 record (4 s.) 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm.
    - Durrell, "Brend", 1948; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 1)
      Magnetic tape. 7 in. reel.
      - Durrell, Brend, 1948 November 7; yrlsc_110_139_01; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:58) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 1)
        CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
        Scope and Contents
        Transcribed from container: "Miller, Henry- Durrell "Brend""
    - "Goldilocks and the three bears", 1948; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 2)
      - Goldilocks and The Three Bears, 1948 November 7; yrlsc_110_139_02; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:53) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 2)
        Content Note: Henry Miller reading from The Rosey Crucifixion
    - Interview conducted by George Wickes (1 of 2), 1961; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 3)
      Interview conducted in London. This unedited interview was the basis for The Art of Fiction: XXVIII, edited by George Wickes. Magnetic tape. 7 in. reel. 3 3/4 in. per sec.
      - Interview conducted by George Wickes (1 of 2), 1961 August 12; yrlsc_110_139_03; Wickes, George; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:00:58) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 3)
        Content Note: Interview conducted in London. This unedited interview was the basis for The Art of Fiction: XXVIII, edited by George Wickes.
    - Interview conducted by George Wickes (2 of 2), 1961; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 4)
      - Interview conducted by George Wickes (2 of 2), 1961 August 12; yrlsc_110_139_04; Wickes, George; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:50:19) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 4)
    - Miller-Durrell Meeting. Recording of meeting in Powell Library, UCLA, 1968; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 5)
      On magnetic tape. Meeting began at 2:30 p.m. Recorded at 3 3/4 in. per sec. Meeting was arranged by Robert Snyder to film scenes for his documentary, "The Henry Miller Odyssey." Persons present at the meeting include: Henry Miller, Lawrence Durrell, etc.
      - Miller-Durrell Meeting. Recording of meeting in Powell Library, UCLA, 1968 March 21; yrlsc_110_139_05; Durrell, Lawrence; Robitaille, Gérald; Wickes, George; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:37:57) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 5)
        Content Note: Meeting began at 2:30 p.m. Recorded at 3 3/4 in. per sec. Meeting was arranged by Robert Snyder to film scenes for his documentary, "The Henry Miller Odyssey." Persons present at the meeting include: Henry Miller, Lawrence Durrell, Gerald Robitaille, George Wicks, Robert Snyder, Jerome Edelstein, Wilbur Smith, Brooke Whiting, and photographers
    - Wild Lines. Interview with Henry Miller by Tom Schiller (1 of 2), 1973; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 6)
      Retaped from 19 reels to 2. Made in connection with Shiller's film, "Henry Miller Asleep and Awake." Tape recording. 3 3/4 in. per sec.
      - Wild Lines. Interview with Henry Miller by Tom Schiller (1 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_110_139_06a; Schiller, Tom; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:35:48) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 6)
        Content Note: Retaped from 19 reels to 2. Made in connection with Shiller's film, " Henry Miller Asleep and Awake." Tape recording. 3 3/4 in. per sec.
      - Wild Lines. Interview with Henry Miller by Tom Schiller (1 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_110_139_06b; Schiller, Tom; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:36:45) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 6)
    - Wild Lines. Interview with Henry Miller by Tom Schiller (2 of 2), 1973; 1 items. (Box 139, Folder 7)
      - Wild Lines. Interview with Henry Miller by Tom Schiller (2 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_110_139_07; Schiller, Tom; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:23:20) 7 inches (Box 139, Case 7)
  - Film, 1971-1973; 2 oversized boxes
    This subseries consists of motion pictures regarding or featuring Henry Miller and several unidentified films. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Scenario also called Alraune." Magnetic tape. Audio. 1/4 in. (1 of 3), undated; 1 items. (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - "Scenario also called Alraune." Magnetic tape. Audio. 1/4 in. (2 of 3), undated; 1 items. (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - "Scenario also called Alraune." Magnetic tape. Audio. 1/4 in. (3 of 3), undated; 1 items. (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Schiller, Tom. "Henry Miller Sleep and Awake." Motion Picture. 35 min. Color. 16mm., 1973; 1 items. (Box 131, Folder 4)
      Produced by Tom Schiller. Print no. 6. A Film of Henry Miller describing pictures hanging in his bathroom.
    - "Poète Maudit." Motion Picture. 6 mm. (1 of 2), undated; 1 items. (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - "Poète Maudit." Motion Picture. 6 mm. (2 of 2), undated; 1 items. (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Snyder, Robert. "Henry Miller: Reflections on Writing." Motion Picture. 55 min. Color. 16mm., 1971; 1 items. (Box 132, Folder 3)